John Emmanuel Galang

Software Developer

Philippines ■ +63 956 879 8747 ■ imman.galang@gmail.com ■ LinkedIn ■ GitHub ■ Portfolio

A full-stack software developer with 1+ years of experience with a hands-on approach, well-developed skills in agile methodology, and an user focused philosophy. I display an expert skill in TypeScript and supporting languages, libraries, and frameworks that solve real-world problems through code. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run with projects independently.

Highlights of Expertise

- React, Next JS, Angular JS
- Bootstrap, Tailwind, Material UI
- Figma, Jira, Confluence

- Nodejs, Express,
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Prisma
- Git, GitHub, Bitbucket

Career Experience

Full Stack React Developer - February 2022 - October 2022

GameMyBiz (React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Storybook)

- Developed a full-stack web application where companies can have their KPI's gamified by integrating points and gameboards for a more enjoyable work for their employees.
- Transformed front-end from vanilla JavaScript to React.
- Oversaw a team of 3 software engineers to write scalable code for our developing SaaS product.
- Built and maintained 100% back-end REST services using Node that served data to our React front-end.
- Tested software for bugs and operating speed, fixing bugs, and documenting processes to increase efficiency

React Developer - March 2022 - August 2022

10x Ventures (TypeScript, Next JS, Node, Prisma, PostgreSQL)

- Developed a web application using Twitter API to help SaaS start-ups, ecommerce stores, coaches, and marketers to get leads and have their first customers/users.
- Worked with an agile scrum team, contributing 100% continuous improvement and development (CICD), helped prioritize scope feature requests to ensure that the biggest impact features were worked on first.
- Developed new features to our application that uses Twitter API such as bulk messaging and bulk adding of leads as requested features from user feedbacks.
- Participated in code reviews with developer team and gained feedback from senior developers and experience in writing custom, scalable code.

Full Stack Web Developer - December 2021 to February 2021

Freelancer

• Built websites for clients from simple static webpages, up to large scale web applications with front-end and back-end from scratch. Design the user interface and ensures optimal user experience.

Education

Zuitt Coding Bootcamp, 2021

Front-end, Back-end, and Full-stack Development

University of the Philippines Los Baños, 2015-2019

Bachelor of Science degree